Chairman Rowe,
and no alternates or anything to be seated.
Anybody have any changes
or
additions to the agenda?
So now we'll move to approval of minutes.
We have the minutes
for the meeting of June 6
and the preceding hearing.
Does anyone
note any
changes, typos,
anything
that needs to be corrected
or revised
in the minutes?
I did not.
>> Neither did I.
Bill, are you okay with the minutes?
>> Yes, I did read them, and they were fine as far as I could tell.
Okay,
I'll move then to approve those minutes.
I'll second.
So, roll call vote,
Commissioner Larson. Aye.
Commissioner Monroe.
Aye.
>> And I also vote aye, so the motion carries three-zero-zero.
We have no public to comment,
so and we have no business
to take care of. So, we'll skip right down to item number seven,
a report from the agent
regarding actions or enforcements.
Joe, I believe you have two on the agenda there. Yeah, one the first one, the
>> 22 Dash 07,
the 196 Lake Road. I'm still
waiting for more information for that one.
It's a yeah. Like a small addition and a new deck.
But, yeah, he he still has to submit a site plan and stuff. And maybe depending on how big the addition is, it might need a nutrient worksheet.
I'm gonna figure that out when when we get it in.
And then the other one was
I had it written as pending, but I actually approved it today. It was a 340 Lake Road
steel septic tank that they're replacing with a with a new one with a effluent filter,
pretty much in the same spot.
So almost pretty straightforward.
>> Okay,
well, I guess
no other business. Then we have item eight, other business.
As Judge just pointed out, I did draft an annual report
to submit to the town.
Hope that you've had a chance to review it,
and
I'm open to any comments, suggestions,
Corrections.
You thought it looked good George
Okay.
Bill, did you have any comments on the?
I haven't seen it.
>> Okay, it was in the well, of course, if you don't have email, you wouldn't have seen it, but
Yeah. It was included in the
submission that
Joe sent out for the
when he sent out the notice for the meeting, he attached that.
Okay, then if you haven't had a chance to look at it, we can hold off on
requesting an approval
until our next meeting.
Okay. We
are scheduled
as usual for election of officers at the first meeting in July.
I will
say that I am willing to serve another year
as Chairman of the Commission.
I don't
I haven't heard anything from
Ed Smith
regarding his nominal role as vice chairman,
and
of course, we are still
lacking
both regular and alternate members,
so it's not like we have a big pool
to draw from here,
or for that matter,
a lot of competition for the slot.
>> I know last year, Bill was concerned that he hadn't had enough, very
much run time on the commission.
Now that he's got an extra year.
What
do you think, Bill?
>> Oh,
I would just like to be stay
as a
regular member for now, if that's okay.
>> It's not like the vice chairman
has a
vital role to play here since we, I think, agreed last year that if I wasn't going to be able to make the meeting, we just wouldn't have the meeting.
And
until we get more members,
I don't see that actually changing
since we're operating with a bare quorum
as it is.
So, how about we say
Chairman Elliott is reelected by acclamation?
I'll second that.
>> Okay.
And if you want a formal vote, Commissioner Larson?
Aye.
Commissioner Monroe?
>> And what the heck? I'll vote aye also.
So, the motion carries three-zero-zero.
And
I think we will just have to hold in abeyance
an
election of a vice chairman
should it I mean, we call for it in the bylaws, but as you say, I don't think it's really a vital role to perform
under the circumstances.
>> And we don't have one in Wyndham.
Usually, if our chairman can't attend, then we usually just
appoint somebody during the meeting
>> so to act as chairman. Acting chairman pro tem.
Well, maybe we should revise that in the bylaws since
bylaws are next, the review of the bylaws.
I hadn't,
I mean, our bylaws were last revised
in 2021,
so they are
fairly fresh.
I'm not aware of any statutory
changes, you know, like
FOI or ME we would have to address.
But Section five, officers and their duties,
Section 5.1
reads,
The offices of the Commission will consist of a chairperson and a vice chairman
vice chairperson, excuse me.
We
could
amend that
to
remove the and a vice chairman.
>> You
wouldn't feel good about
voting Ed in as a vice chair again?
>> Well, given that he's not present at the meeting,
I suppose we could go ahead and do that.
But again,
we'll take it as a suggestion
without acting on it that
maybe we don't really need
a vice chairperson.
And
I will,
again, I will
renew my contact to Ed
and see if, again, see how he feels about
continuing to serve nominally
as vice chairman, again, per bylaws?
Or
alternatively,
do we want to just strike that office
and
further references
to the vice chair
that occur in Section five
of the bylaws.
You know, again, it just doesn't
have an urgent
feeling to it.
We still have vacancies, as I previously mentioned. We did have one inquiry,
but that person is, I guess, intending
to build in Andor they're a property owner and intending to move here, but
obviously not yet a registered voter, and so ineligible
to serve on the Commission.
But
all we can do, I suppose, is to continue to advertise.
And
maybe if we resign en masse,
that would prompt the
Board of Selectmen to take more drastic action.
I have nine on the agenda.
Oh, any other business?
Questions, comments, whatever?
>> I guess I had two,
well, maybe just one comment to, no, two. Okay, now I remember what it is. Two comments for Joe just to
go out and take a look at. I know several months ago we
were, I can't remember if was we or I think you approved, Joe, a
driveway
going in up, I'm going to say 13
West Street,
right up the hill,
because it was in proximity
in an upland review area.
And I noticed that they have done significant clearing on that lot. And I don't recall
any discussion
about clearing
when
when we talked about the driveway.
So I would ask you to take a take a look at that and make sure
it's all the way that you want it there. Yeah, looks like
>> Did drive by it.
I probably should actually go up and walk the property.
But it looked like it was pretty close to. I mean, they did all the clearing, but a lot of that clearing is.
Outside the up Upland Review area. I think most of it is. Most of it is. Yep. Because there's just a little, like, a corner where that
>> Okay. I couldn't remember. I just remembered if the driveway was
close by.
>> Yeah, it must be a lot. First I was kind of surprised too. I was like, oh man, and then I brought the plan up and you know, at it from the road and it looked like it was kind of lining up.
Approximately the way it was designed.
It just looked bigger than it
than I thought. Okay,
>> yep, very good. I guess the second one, as I was
looking through,
I don't know what made me go look at 344
Lake Road, and that's the big addition going on. And in the file I saw, Joe, where you had
taken a bunch of pictures within the last week or so of
the erosion and sediment control in there.
And
this is just, you know, for, I guess, Commission members
knowledge. I went back and as I walked by there, it looks to me like there's wetlands down in that area
on the property.
And
I didn't go back and look today, I'll look tomorrow morning, but I was surprised
extent of
loading
dirt, you know, the number of truckloads of dirt that they hauled in to spread around that.
And
as I looked at the site plan
that was previously approved and we did it in addition to it,
it didn't show any wetlands on that
piece of property.
And so then I went back to the GIS map on the wetlands
and it shows wetlands through there where
at least I see the skunk cabbage and that kind of stuff, I think. Good indicator.
Yep,
going down there. And so,
you know,
I know I have been fussing a little bit about not having wetlands delineated on
site maps. And going back to this one, it appears that there should have been wetlands delineated
on the map. I don't know if we've
filled it in or not. I was surprised how far down the hill there that they spread that 10 loads of dirt around that they had brought in. So anyhow,
that's, you know, when
we say we should have the wetlands at least delineated
on
site plan,
that's one of the reasons,
you know, I think there are wetlands there and I think we probably,
I don't know if we filled it in or not. Joe, you might take a look at it. Think they're a little further.
>> Okay, yep. Down because I remember looking at that and I had to look at the plan.
That one was a little weird because
we had
the original permit
that was before I was around. Yep. And it had more. The the limit of clearing was about where it is right now.
But then
so that was approved, and that's technically still valid. And then we approved modification that had less clearing.
So Yeah. Okay. I didn't look at the original. I just I think they might have modification, they said. Doesn't look like find
the two, and I wasn't really sure if we really had
much to go off of because both, you know, it was approved.
Yep.
>> So that's just for us as commission members that, you know, we we need to do our due diligence to make sure that we know where the wetlands are Yeah, and specifically in the approval state, you know,
>> maybe a little more
bluntly, I guess. Don't know. We'll just have to look out for that in the future.
Okay, that was all I had, George.
>> Well, point well taken, and
glad you made that observation.
I think often the presumption that for things around the lake, the 200 foot review area is from the lake, but in fact,
there are plenty of wetlands
in addition to the lake per se.
As you said, Skunk Cow Beach is
a recognized indicator
for poorly drained soils.
Okay,
if that's all of the
other business we have to take care of,
item number nine, our next regular meeting will be on Monday, August 1.
Again, same time, same place.
I know that one
item on the agenda will be a report from Hank Gruner
summarizing the
wetlands survey
that we conducted,
that the
well, it was commissioned,
co sponsored,
and the vernal pools,
I went out and visited a few vernal pools. It was an interesting exercise,
and it should be a
good report
and
a valuable addition to our knowledge about the
wetlands
that we are
trying to protect
here in Andover.
George,
>> I do have two other Yeah. Two other things, if I And,
you know, one, I can't remember if I mentioned it last time, but
the,
the subdivision
in two house
two house lots up at 26
Old Farms Road or 26 Pine Ridge, you know, from both. I
know that
there's
discussion going on that they want to
redo
the house off of
Old Farms Road
to have the driveway come in from Pine Ridge.
There's some reason that they couldn't come in from the top like they originally planned,
And I don't recall where that driveway is going to go with respect
to the wetlands or not. But we, I think Joe, you should at least be seeing something
from Jim on that at some point going forward till you get a cut on it.
The other one just
to share
is that we're wrapping up the gravel pit operation
over there
by the gas station on Route 6.
In our meeting next Monday,
we
should be getting
the restoration plan for that. I don't know if Joe you've got any interest
in that or not. I think the
Commission will end up doing a sidewalk out there just
because we have a hard time seeing what it is Chris
Bell's talking about
on that busy drawing and we'll go out there just to have
him walk us through it. But if you've got interest in that, you're certainly welcome to
join us on that one coming up.
And that's
it. Normally I take information from wetlands and go back to planning and zoning, but here's a couple that we can actually
have it go back, share it with you guys.
>> Okay.
Yeah, presumably,
old farms
Pine Ridge
would be
simply using the
driveway that we've already permitted
and extending it
in the other direction.
>> Right. And
it will be in an upland review area. Yeah. I don't think it'll be through any wetlands, but I haven't seen the drawing yet.
Right. When I talked to Jim about it, he said, Well, it's got to go through wetlands review before we do anything with it. Okay.
>> Well, we'll look forward to seeing that then,
and
thanks for that input.
Okay, so
absent any further comments,
we are poised to item 10
on the agenda, which would be adjournment.
Do we have a motion?
I move we adjourn.
>> I'll second it. I second it. Okay,
seconded by Mr. Monroe.
All right, then by
unanimous consent,
I think we may stand adjourned.
Thanks for popping in tonight. I'm glad we were able to keep it short. It's an awfully hot and muggy evening,
and
brings out a certain lassitude,
if you will.
Namely, I want to go out to the hammock
and rock gently
and enjoy the breeze.
>> So Well, thank you, Abby, for all your work Thank you, for Abby, and thank you. We'll send you out with a very easy set of minutes for this meeting. Know. Know. Planning and zoning will be quite too easy next week.
>> But thank you for this parting gift and thank you all for teaching me a lot and being patient with me and my learning curve. So I've had a really great time and y'all are really great people to learn from.
Good luck to you, Abby. Thank
you. Thank you so much. And
have you harvested the garlic?
Oh, yes. Oh, yes. It's gonna be donated soon.
>> Yeah. Saw a piece on Eric's desk the other day. He was Oh, yeah. A vampire's warrior or something. Yep. Yep. The garlic family, ferry came to town hall. Yep.
Goodnight.
Goodnight everyone. Goodnight all.
Alright.